Guide to the Nathan Comfort Starr Arthuriana Ephemera Collection, 1915 - 1979
Nathan Comfort Starr Arthuriana Ephemera Collection, 1915-1979
- Materials Removed from Starr Book Collection
  - Works... Spenser: Postcard of Holyrood Palace and Arthur Seat, blank; School picture set Number 15: King Arthur and his knights (Env. with 17 cards w/facsimile illustrations and descriptions), PR2350 1679 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Observations on the Faerie Queene of Spenser: Clipping: review of different volume, referencing Observations [?], PR2358.W3 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Odes by Mr. Gray: Engraved plate of Horatio Walpole, Fourth Earl of Orford (engr. J. Cochran); Clipping: Article, A Strawberry Hill Forgery, 1940; Clipping: Facsim. of Strawberry Hill illustration by T. Rowlandson, 4 May 1940, PR3502.O5 1757 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Moral and political dialogues...: Letter from NCS to Sarah Brewer; Letter from Richard Hurd, Bishop of Lichfield, addressed Dear Sir, 13 January 1780, PR3517.H78 M6 1771 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Legend of Camelot: Child's drawing, labeled King Arthur – note on back: Drawn by Margot, 22 December 1937; Clipping: bookseller's catalog, PR4630.E98 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - The famous tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall: Clipping: review, 1 December 1923; Clipping: photo of Hardy monument, 1929-30?, PR4750.F3 1923 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Hawker of Morwenstow: Clipping: review, 1 August 1975; Clipping: article, Hawker Centenary, 1 August 1975, PR4759.H9 Z63 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The life of Sir Aglovale de Galis: Clipping: review, 26 March 1954, PR4809.H17 L5 1954 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Five Arthurian poems: Publisher's advertisement, PR5074.A1 1902 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The misfortunes of Elphin: Hand-written notes, PR5162.M58 1829 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - King Arthur's laureate: Letter from Frances Lium to NCS, 9 February 1977, PR5560.E3 1971 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - The madness of Merlin: Clipping: advertisement, 21 December 1946; Clipping: review, 12 April 1947, PR6003.I75 M3 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - The crimson chalice: Hand-written notes, PR6005.A486 C75 1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - The sword and the flame: Hand-written notes, PR6005.H65 S96 1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Tristram: Clipping: review, 12 July 1934, PR6021.E63 T7 1934 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The little wench: Bookseller's compliments; Clipping: review, Now Wait a Minute, Casey!, 17 July 1965, PR6023.I5817 L57 1935 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Badon parchments: Letter from John Masefield to NCS, 1954; Letter from Masefield to NCS, PR6025.A77 B23 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Maiden Castle: Clipping: review, 28 March 1966; Clipping: article on John Cowper Powys, 12 August 1955, PR6031.O867 M33 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The masque of the Grail: Advertisement: Enid, a new British opera; Advertisement: The postbag: an Irish operetta, PR6035.R347 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Merlin, or the return of Arthur: Letter from F.J.H. Sanders to NCS, 27 January 1949; Letter from Sanders to NCS, 24 June 1952; Card of F.J.H. Sanders, PR6037.K42 M4 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - The return of Arthur: Harvard Bulletin, 1955, PR6037.K42 R42 1955 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - The return of Arthur, pt. 2: Publisher's advertisement, PR6037.K42 R4 1959 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - The return of Arthur: Clipping: advertisement, 19 May 1966; Letter from Sebastian Carter to NCS, 1975, PR6037.K42 R42 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - The eagles have flown: Clipping: review, 19 November 1954, PR6039.R38 E3 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - The great captains: Clipping: review, 18 March 1956; Clipping: review, 4 May 1956, PR6039.R38 G8 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - The last enchantment: Clipping: article on Mary Stewart, 2 September 1979, PR6039.T46 L3 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - The book of Merlyn: Clipping: review, 21 April 1978; Clipping: review, 27 November 1977; Clipping: review of Percival and the presence of God, 14 July 1978, PR6045.H2 B6 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - T.H. White: a biography: Clipping: review, 21 April 1968; Clipping: review, 7 December 1967; Hand-written notes, PR6045.H2 Z9 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Arthurian triptych: Hand-written notes; Offprint review, Modern Language Quarterly, Vol. 22, No. 1, March 1961 with note from publisher, PR6045.I5 Z85 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Charles Williams: a critical essay: Clipping: review, 13 November 1966, PR6045.I5 Z87 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - The finger and the moon: Clipping: review, 23 August 1973, PR6054.S457 F5 1973 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Tristan and Iseult in Cornwall: Publisher's advertisement; Letter from E. M. R. Ditmas to NCS, 24 September 1970, PR6054.I8 T7 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Percival and the presence of God: Receipt from publisher, PR6058.U535 P47 1978 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - The crystal cave: Postcard of King Arthur's Castle, Tintagel, Cornwall, blank, PR6069.T46 C7 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Sunrise trumpets: Manuscript: hand-written poem, Yeseult by Joseph Auslander; Clipping: obituary for Auslander, 24 June 1965; Clipping: review, 26 April 1924, PS3501.U67 S8 1924 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Salisbury Plain: Clipping: review, 30 April 1965, PS3503.R264 S35 1965 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - New adventures: Letter from Wilmon Brewer to NCS, 30 November 1977; Compliments of the author card, PS3503.R513 N4 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - The silver chalice: Clipping: review, 27 July 1952, PS3505.O818 S5 1953 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - The round table: Letter from Wilmon Brewer to NCS, 13 October 1956; Letter from Dorothy B. Greene to NCS, 3 November 1956, PS3515.R4525 R6 1955 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Kinsmen of the Grail: Letter from Katie [no last name] to NCS, PS3535.O15 K5 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - The enchanted cup: Clipping: advertisement, 3 October 1953; Clipping: advertisement, 25 October 1953, PS3535.O17 E6 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Launcelot, my brother: Clipping: review, 26 September 1954; Clipping: advertisement, 3 October 1954, PS3535.O17 L38 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Collected poems... Robinson: Publisher's advertisement for Nicodemus: a book of poems, PS3535.O25 A17 1922 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Tristram: Photograph, birthplace of Edwin Arlington Robinson at Head Tide, ME, 14 August 1958; Envelope with pressed leaf from fern outside Robinson's cabin in Peterborough, NH, 23 August 1950, PS3535.O25 T75 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Edwin Arlington Robinson: Clipping: Winters wins Yale Poetry Prize, 9 January 1961, PS3535.O25 Z94 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - The transformation of Merlin: Letter from Byron Rogers to NCS, 21 May 1970; Letter from A.O.H. Jarman to NCS, 7 June 1970; Letter from Armel H. Diverres to NCS, 14 June 1970, PS3535.O25 Z6548 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Refuge in Avalon: Clipping: review, 7 November 1963, PS3537.T238 R3 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Arthur Rex: Clipping: advertisement, 1979; Clipping: article on Andrew Greeley, 25 June 1979, PS3552.E719 A7 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - The queen's knight: Clipping: advertisement, 17 March 1955, PS3552.O759 Q445 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Sword of the winds: Clipping: review, 15 December 1957, PS3556.A95 S9 1957 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Excalibur: Clipping: review, 1973, PS3562.A82 E93 1973 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Lancelot: Clipping: review, 28 October 1977; Copy of a sermon by the Rev. Lee A. Felford, Ph.D. at The Church of the Epiphany, NY, 18 August 1979 (references novel), PS3566.E6912 L3 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - The quest for Excalibur: Clipping: review, 15 November 1959; Clipping: review, 11 December 1959, PS3573.I2 Q4 1959 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Ulrich Füetrer's Parzival: Clipping: review, 26 December 1936, PT1522.F8 B6 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Tristan und Îsolt: Clipping: review, 19 May 1945, PT1525.A2 C5 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - The anatomy of love: Clipping: review, 21 April 1972, PT1526.J3 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Lanzelet: Publisher's advertisement, PT1661.U8 L32 1951 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Parzival...: Publisher's advertisement for Gregorius, a Medieval Oedipus Legend by Hartmann von Aue, PT1682.P8 E59 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Characterization and individuality in Wolfram's 'Parzival': Receipt from publisher, PT1688.B5 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Wolfram von Eschenbach's Parzival: Clipping: review, 17 May 1974; Abstract, Wolfram von Eschenbach's Parzival: an attempt at a total evaluation, 1973, PT1688.K7 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Studies of Wolfram von Eschenbach: Clipping: review, 27 June 1958, PT1688.R5 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Prophetia Anglicana & Romana...: Hand-written notes, QB26.M56 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - The curtana or sword of mercy: Letter from E. M. R. Ditmas to NCS, 5 March 1967, U856.E54 D58 1966 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Bibliographical Bulletin of the Intl. Arthurian Society: Letter from William Roach to NCS, 1 February 1965; Letter from John L. Grigsby to NCS, 10 October 1972; Letter from Grigsby to NCS, 3 December 1976; Card from Barbara Thorpe, 1977?; New Year's card from [illegible]; Advertisement for Théodore Hersart de la Villemarqué; Announcement regarding publication of the bulletin, 1968?; Announcement regarding meeting of the Intl. Arthurian Congress, 1966; Clipping: obituary of Lewis Thorpe, 17 October 1977, Z8045.I5 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - A bibliography of critical Arthurian literature: Type-written manuscript: A preliminary bibliography of Arthurian literature for 1930; Type-written manuscript: Bibliography of recent English and American versions of the Arthurian stories, Z8045.M69 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - The Arthurian legend (Newberry checklist): Type-written manuscript: Note on the Arthurian collection for the library handbook by NCS, Z8045.N53 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Bibliography of modern Arthurian retellings: Hand-written notes, Z8045.N6 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Le morte d'Arthur with Beardsley illustrations: Clipping: letter regarding publication of J.M. Dent's reprinting of Caxton's edition of Malory (1485) with Beardsley illustrations, 31 March 1945, Z8545.5 .W3 1945 (Box 4, Folder 96)